see
you
next time.
No.
Hey, fancy meeting you
here. You remember me?
How dare you ask such a thing, wretch!
I can only dream of
forgetting you one day!
I lost count of how often
I've tasted death hunting you!
Well, that's nice to see that
you're all right, at least.
You'll be all right when I have your head!
And yet, firstly I must
restore my bygone honor.
In our previous battle, you no doubt
coerced those villagers into voting for you.
But now, as you can plainly see, this
untainted specimen has fallen to my wiles.
Isn't that right, dear?
Please say that you'll marry me.
Not this again.
I would cast aside my life for you.
I am but a simple man with
a wife and two children.
But none of that matters.
We can start a new family.
Oh, you're a special kind
of dirtbag, aren't you?
So, you acknowledge her
superior beauty. What? No!
You have any idea what kind of
money I spent to obtain this elf?
The kind where I can't
simply give her away.
I give.
You win this round. Go me!
How dare you give up so easily! Enough!
You think I would let
a heathen trollop and
some worthless losers
tarnish my honor yet again?
No!
I call you out, woman!
You against me!
One decisive vote!
Not as again!
You do realize you're fighting over
who's getting sacrificed, don't you?
From what I've heard, the squid fishing
here in the village had all but dried up.
And then out of nowhere,
some kind of giant-talking squid
creature appeared and restocked the lake.
As compensation, it asked
for a living sacrifice.
Apparently, it has some particular tastes.
What I'm looking for is a real cutie.
Not too chesty, I like
the itty-bitty types.
It's someone who's a bit on the vain side,
but is also the kind of gal who's not
afraid to bite back when you want her to.
Know what I mean?
That is a very specific
list of preferences.
Right, let's go.
It also said that if anyone
ever tried to harm it,
it would take back the lake's bounty.
So it has the village hostage.
That complicates things.
Why kidnap my companion though?
They already have the elf.
It's a lot more complicated than that.
Apparently,
whoever finds the next sacrifice will
then become the village's next leader.
That's stupid.
And since they both meet the requirements,
either one could be sacrificed.
You sure about that?
Somehow I doubt your friend could
surpass an elf in terms of looks.
Well, she's already done it once before.
Sorry, but I find it hard to believe
that anyone could be that beautiful.
Believe it.
I've seen my share of lovely women.
There is none in this or any
world as beautiful as her.
So that's how it is. True love.
No, you're jumping to conclusions.
By the way, why are you
still following me around?
This is about what I did to your card,
I'm sorry, but I can't
pay you back right now.
Oh, don't worry about that.
I've decided I'm going to find a new job.
Trading in exotic goods hasn't
been a very romantic career,
mostly just guilt-inducing.
This has been fun, you and me.
I'd love to continue traveling with
you till I find myself a better gig.
Fine, then.
But if my companion has met with any
harm, I will not hesitate to strike.
Yes, she's lucky to have you.
It's not like that!
Come on, we mustn't keep
your sweet lady waiting.
Hey, slow down!
Perfect!
If I were storing a sacrifice,
I'd use one of these.
What's wrong?
It's good.
Right in Rome, I guess.
So why are we eating and not
out looking for my friend?
Well, I don't know about you, but
I'm more useful with a full stomach.
What better way for us to get to know
each other than with a meal, right?
You agree?
I see no purpose in being
friendly with humans.
Especially not you two.
Your company all but spoils the food.
I want you to die.
Horribly.
In untold pain.
I've never seen a meal
make someone so happy.
By my hand.
I think even the squid likes it.
Both of you.
I see you've freed
yourself from that harpy.
Is this your new traveling companion?
Recent events brought us together.
But speaking of my friend, I was
hoping you could answer something.
Yes, I was captured along with that woman.
They moved her before you arrived.
She's to be sacrificed at the festival.
you will tell me where
she is my what rage you
have don't tempt me hey
let's all calm down shall
we I'm not done talking to you yet look
at me I need to know where she is how
long has it been since I was graced with
a hot meal I'd long forgotten the comfort
one could bring ever since this lowly
creature busted me i've been captured by
barbarians nearly killed by shoddy
cartography more than once treated as a petty
thief and enslaved and
sold to be sacrificed
it's humiliating
fine heretic it seems
our only way forward is to form a truce
a truce i will help you in exchange you
will help me get my revenge are you aware
that the humans of the village revere
giant squid creature as a god that in mind
imagine what might happen if someone say
slaughtered the beast right in front
of their eyes kill the squid and you'll
wreck the festival and the village along
with it interesting that's a good idea
interrupting the festival could work in
our favor but it won't be as simple as that
you know defeating a monster of its size
and capabilities without help will be next
to impossible all right let's kill it
hey were you even listening to me i had
already made up my mind to kill the thing
before our paths crossed
again splendid not
only is it intelligent it lives in the
middle of a lake how would you even be able
to draw it out don't worry it'll be all
right we've got this just leave it to me
just leave it to me just leave it to me
just leave it to me I take it from that
look in your eye that you have a plan
I do one that requires your assistance
if we're going to do this we need to be
able to trust each other implicitly will
you give me your word not to run when
the time comes this man has an enemy he's
Flexing.
But as an ally, he's reliable.
No, comforting.
He's smart, strong, level-headed.
And in the right light,
he's almost handsome.
I swear, on the name of my great goddess,
you have my full support in this endeavor.
So, I see this is what you
meant when you said trust.
May I ask what I'm tied to at least?
Floats. Come again?
We're fishing for squid, and
we need bait, so here we are.
Here's hoping you don't drown.
Let's go!
It's a freaky heretic!
I was a fool to trust a human!
This is quite the plan
you've come up with.
It's exciting.
However, it does also beg a few questions.
The biggest of which being how you
were able to throw her that far.
Strange.
I should have been able to get her
at least a bit further from shore.
Oh.
What's going on?
Well, you have been under
a lot of stress lately.
I could work some of that out
for you if you'd be up for it.
Oh, no.
I'm perfectly fine. Are you sure?
I am quite skilled. You know?
I don't see any need for
you to be that close.
Oh.
Would you like some dried squid?
Oh, silly me.
You have your hands full.
Hang on, I can just
feed it to you. Say, ah.
It's just the two of us now,
so let's have a little fun.
Wait for me, Tachibana.
I will kill this squid
and then come save you.
I can't grab you, someone, or I fall!
Don't worry, you're doing a great job!
Yay!
It's so...
Strange this squid still has flavor.
It's said to have a taste that can
last you for an entire lifetime.
It's starting to feel that way.
We've been here for hours.
How is the bait holding up?
It's hard to tell.
I haven't noticed any
movement for a while now.
Hey, old man!
Are you fishing for squid?
Correct. You idiot!
That's not gonna work!
Everyone knows squids are nocturnal!
Is this how it ends?
No, I'll find a way to endure.
That squid has to die first, and then
I will finally bust those heretics.
Look! Over there!
Oh, yeah!
Celebrate later! Save me first!
I've been treasuring this precious
nut since our lady gifted it to me,
but now it seems to have dried up.
What are you saying?
It's just a nut.
I fear this may mean that something
awful has happened to the premiere.
The look on your face says
something, but it's not fear.
Although you are kind
of scaring me right now.
Remember, the flavor lasts a lifetime,
so you can keep chewing and chewing.
If this is the last thing I'll
ever see, I'm glad it's beautiful.
All right, time to prep the sacrifice.
It's too soon.
I'm not ready.
I don't have a plan.
Okay, thanks, Bast.
Maybe if we put up a fight?
Who am I kidding?
It's gonna eat me!
Or strangle me!
Or drown me!
Or something for a worse!
No!
I don't want to die!
Not at the tentacles of a squid!
So not cool.
This isn't the way the food chain works.
Come on.
Humans are supposed to eat you
guys, not the other way around.
I'm gonna need a little
break from talking to you.
Oh, and of course we had to pick
now to be in the middle of a fight!
Come to think of it, this
is a lot like back then.
Ah, you're my only hope, Jake Gucci!
I tried, I really did, but I can't
understand a word the teacher says, please!
Please, you gotta help me!
You're failing because
you sleep through class.
This is your own fault.
But I've got a part-time job!
And?
Come on, these are life
or death stakes here!
My summer vacation is on the line!
Fine, then.
Just how bad are your grades?
Super bad.
For the last time, explain it to
me in a way that I can understand!
I'm trying to help you stop yelling at me.
It's so hard!
Which is why you asked for my help.
We can go over it again, alright?
And focus this time?
We both know all you need
to do is apply yourself.
All right, we'll start
back at the beginning.
You just don't understand.
Why would you?
You're good at everything
and I'm just a loser!
Hey, Tachibana!
You stupid, useless eggplant!
I never want to speak to you again!
Wait, what? Eggplant?
And so, the two friends did not speak
to each other for a little over a week.
Which made school not the
least bit awkward, is it?
All that, and I still lost my summer
vacation to make up tests and extra lessons.
Darn it!
Now I'm really on my own and
I still don't have a plan!
What am I going to do?
That's right!
All I need to do is charm them and
they'll turn against each other!
I just have to get this thing off my head!
Get off of me!
What are you doing?
Stop shaking the cage!
Jake!
Hey, who forgot to lock the cage?
Sorry, that was me.
So, she all right?
Are you even listening?
It's a goddess.
I didn't think it'd put
up this big of a fight.
You said you had a plan,
didn't you? Somewhat.
I assumed I could just
yank it out of the lake.
Why would you assume that?
What's wrong?
Why is my strength failing me?
My diet is still perfectly balanced.
I keep up with my morning routine.
I see no reason why I should
be struggling with this.
So why is everything off?
There she is.
Kill her!
Bring her down!
Please, settle down! What?
There's a moth?
Hey!
Tachibana!
She's nothing but a witch!
That tart tried to steal
my husband from me!
Goddess!
I want at least three children with you!
Pick me!
I want at least four!
Now, hold on!
This girl is meant to be an
offering to the squid gun!
God!
Seriously!
Why does the worst stuff
always have to happen to me?
Enough with this self-pity
already, you home-wrecking tramp!
Those crocodile tears
may work on our husbands,
but they won't have any effect on us!
I bet you've never done an
honest day's work in your life!
Beauty is such a burden, isn't it?
Your existence is reason enough
for us to burn you at the stake!
Hear, hear! Oh, yeah?
Well, sorry!
Cause there's no way I'm dying here!
And how dare you judge me?
I haven't done anything!
While you guys do human
sacrifice and for what? Squid?
You're a bunch of idiot murderers!
How dare you badmouth
our precious village!
See?
She is a witch!
She's cursing us!
Don't tell me that girl on
the tower is your companion!
That's right.
You actually think I'm like
this because I want to be?
It's easy to judge people by
their looks or your opinions.
You stand there randomly deciding what a
prison's worth and why, because it's fun?
I am not the problem here!
So don't put your baggage on me!
Like, what human sacrifice?
Why not just make it a
life-size doll and give it that?
Not very shy with her opinions, is she?
Of course not.
Never has been, never will be.
Dr.
Yubana, you okay?
Take a guess!
I'm seconds away from being slaughtered!
I'm on my way now!
I can't hold on for much longer!
Please, hurry up and get over here!
And do something about this
angry mob before they belay me!
Of course!
Oh, wow!
Take this!
Fake girl!
Do you think she's alright?
I'm not sure how long an
elf could survive in there.
She's tougher than she seems to be.
She'll be fine.
Don't abandon your
responsibility like that!
She's in there because of you!
But why, great squid god?
Why did you do that?
I always minding my own business
since you're in a womanly snag.
And then all of a sudden, I'm per -
Serves you right, you pervy cephalopod!
Oh, well, hello there.
You're quite the cutie, aren't you?
Uh, don't even think
about it, Slimeball. Cute!
I'm gonna eat you up!
Hold on, I'm almost there!
Almost is not cutting it!
Oh, you.
At long last, I will see your demise!
Come and let us die together!
Stop it!
Stop it, you weirdo!
Quit trying to get us killed and
finish off this creepy squid!
What did you say?
Premier, use this!
I see.
It was so cold!
I knew that Damascus knife was sharp,
but what you did was something else.
Oh, uh, thank you for saving me, okay?
The pain is unbearable!
It's cruel, queen!
Mmm. Tasty!
Hey, I saw that look.
There's plenty to go around,
so stop ogling my piece.
No, it's just you're eating our god, so...
You think a god tastes this good?
This is nothing more than
delicious giant squid!
No, it can't be.
Heatery.
Miggy, it seems we've been beaten.
My good people, I ask you, is it right to
sacrifice a life to appease a giant squid?
I see now that we were wrong, for
we are not squids, we are human!
Let's never come back here.
And I think we're all in agreement that
this elf shall be our next village head.
Oh, hey, I leveled up.
Hey there, good evening.
Well, you sure adopted quickly.
Is that a good thing?
Everyone seems happy.
I think that's enough.
Hey, so... Huh?
I apologize.
For what?
For your notebook.
Oh my gosh, I completely
forgot about that!
Don't worry about it, I'm over it now.
Honestly, I'm more surprised that you
had something to be embarrassed about.
I guess you're sort of human after all.
Only sort of?
I'm still curious what it was that
you just had to keep me from seeing.
There's no getting back the
info you scribbled over.
Eh, maybe you can show me your own
notebook once we get back to our world.
Sorry, I don't have it anymore.
My grandmother threw it out a while ago.
Oh, gotcha.
That's unfortunate. It is.
Sorry about that.
Please don't leave me again.
It's too dangerous.
Take your eyes off me for
even a moment and I might die.
Very true.
Was that a marriage proposal I heard?
Village head! No!
Village head! I said no!
Please, we desperately need your guidance!
Fine!
Stop chasing me!
When did you get here?
No...
They ate it! What?
The smell is making my mouth
water even this far away.
Let's go try some.
You can make do with
the dried squid we have.
You know, when those two showed up, I had
a suspicion they'd upend our plan somehow.
And yet they surprised me anyway.
Hmph.
There's no way we'd beat Four-Eyes.
He was able to defeat me after all.
Why are you bragging about that?
In any case, we finished our
business here, so we should leave.
Understood.
At least we can bring back
some squid for the demon lord.
So his strength decreases
when they become separated.
Huh.
That gives me a delicious idea.
It's a man, it's a man.
It's a man.
Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go. Yeah! It's a man.
You'll have to say it.
I'm happy.
You're satisfied.
You can't stop.
Thank you
so
much.
So what was your end goal, really?
I just wanted to squeeze
a cute girl, is all.
And now you understand that's super not
cool and the reason you got punished?
Yes.
So have you learned your lesson?
I didn't know there was any squid left.
You're so good.